Jéssica Moreira Batista da Silva

Location: Brussels, BE Telephone: +32 0483816422 Email: jessicambs@live.com

LinkedIn: LinkedIn.com/in/jessicambs/

Professional profile

Self-motivated person with a bachelor's degree in Biotechnology and Bioprocess Engineering. Always willing to learn has a Software Engineering Specialization and currently doing a master's degree in Quantitative Biotechnology in which was awarded the 2020 Master scholarship by the Carolina Foundation.

Competent professional on QA testing with extensive experience in Web applications and is preparing a Master degree Project, related to Systems Biology, with the title "Characterization of molecular heterogeneity in celiac disease patients".

Executive skills

- Pro-active
- Flexible
- Goal-oriented

- Problem-solver
- Team player
- Sociable

Career summary

SEPT 2019 - 2020

Universidad de Zaragoza, Zaragoza-ES

Graduate Research Assistant

Outline

Develop research in RNA-seq gene expression data in the context of auto-immune disorders. As such, it involves the usage of analytical techniques (linear modeling of gene expression & coexpression data, mainly).

Key responsibilities

- Discuss provisional results
- Development of computational routines to analyse celiac disease patients data
- Investigate different topics of statistical modeling and bioinformatics methods in R (Bioconductor libraries)
- Communicate the findings written, orally and papers

JAN 2018 - JUL 2019 MV Sistemas, Recife-BR

Software Quality Assurance Analyst

Outline

Monitors every phase of the development process to ensure that the design and software adhere to company standards.

Key responsibilities

- Development of document risk analysis and document test cases
- Record test progress and results
- Code automated tests and discover bugs within software
- Development of test plans
- Development of innovation and streamline overall testing processes
- Perform manual and automated testing

JAN 2017 - MAR 2017 Biologicus, Recife-BR

Engineering Intern

Outline

Integrated the back-office team pro-actively and efficiently.

Key responsibilities

- Development of new products
- Optimization of the production process
- · Statistical analysis for the improvement of product quality

JAN 2014 - DEC 2016 University of Campina Grande

Assessor at LINA Biotec

Outline

Integration of Biotechnology courses in Brazil, discussing aspects relevant to the consolidation and regulation of Biotechnology professionals.

Education and qualifications

- > Software Engineering Specialization, 9.2/10 Estácio 2020
- ➤ **Biotechnology and Bioprocess Engineering, 8.01/10 -** Federal University of Campina Grande 2017

Awards

Fundación Carolina Scholarship - Student Education Program Graduate -2019/2020

Professional Skills

- ➤ **Programming:** PL/SQL, Python, MATLAB, R, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Linux/Unix, Next-Generation Sequencing data analysis experience,
- > Bioinformatics: BLAST, NCBI, UCSC Genome browser, OMIM, EGA, GEO
- > Office: Word. Excel. PowerPoint
- Continuous integration (CI): Bamboo, Jira, Git, Selenium, Zephyr
- Communication: Excellent organization and communication with an emphasis in presentation

Languages

- Portuguese Native
- > English C1
- > Spanish C1
- French A2

Courses

- > Analyzing Data with Python IBM 2020
- > Analyzing Next-Generation Sequencing Data in R Datacamp 2020
- > RNA-seq with Bioconductor in R_- Datacamp 2020
- > Data Science: Visualização de dados com Python Udemy 2019
- > **Database cration** Apta Cursos 2018
- Algorithms of numerical methods applied to chemical engineering -Buzzero - 2016